Enjoyed by millions for over a decade,
ผู้เล่นนับล้านได้รับ ความสนุกเพลิดเพลินมาเป็นสิบ ๆ ปี
Dota is a game of strategy, momentum and action.
Dota เป็นเกมแนวกลยุทธ์ อัดแน่นด้วยโมเมนตัมและแอ็กชัน
Two teams of five players called Radiant and Dire
2 ทีมที่มีผู้เล่นทีมละ 5 คน เรียกกันว่า Radiant และ Dire
face off in a vast battlefield.
ประจัญหน้ากันในสมรภูมิอันกว้างใหญ่
The first team to destroy the opposing team's Ancient
ทีมแรกที่ทำลาย Ancient ของทีมฝ่ายตรงข้ามได้
will win the match.
จะเป็นผู้ชนะแมตช์
However, there are many steps on the road to the Ancient.
แต่ถนนที่นำไปสู่ Ancient มีหลายขั้นตอน
Before the battle begins each player chooses a unique hero
ก่อนที่การต่อสู้จะเริ่มขึ้น ผู้เล่นแต่ละคนต้องเลือกฮีโร่ที่ไม่ซ้ำใคร
from a pool of over 100 potential fighters,
จากกองกลางที่มีนักสู้ ให้เลือกได้มากกว่า 100 ตัว
each with their own abilities, strengths and weaknesses.
แต่ละตัวมีสกิล จุดแข็ง และจุดอ่อนของตัวเอง
Teams then enter the battlefield
จากนั้นทีมจะเดินหน้าเข้าสู่สมรภูมิ
and compete to slay opposing players,
และแข่งขันกัน เพื่อสังหารผู้เล่นฝ่ายตรงข้าม
or computer-controlled forces called creeps,
หรือกองกำลังที่ควบคุมด้วยคอมพิวเตอร์ เรียกว่าครีป
in order to earn experience
เพื่อให้มีประสบการณ์
to augment their heroes' abilities and gold
ที่จะสั่งสมสกิลให้ฮีโร่ของทีม และโกลด์
to purchase items that increase their heroes' power.
เพื่อซื้อไอเท็มที่จะช่วยเพิ่มพลังของฮีโร่
As players become more powerful,
เมื่อผู้เล่นมีพลังอำนาจมากขึ้น
they will lead their forces to eliminate
ก็จะเป็นผู้นำกองกำลังของตนไปกำจัด
the opposing team's defensive towers
ป้อมคุ้มกันของทีมฝ่ายตรงข้าม
in each of the three lanes that cross the battlefield.
ในแต่ละเลนจาก 3 เลนที่พาดขวางสมรภูมิ
If a team wishes to gain an additional advantage,
หากทีมใดต้องการมีแต้มต่อเพิ่มเติม
they may also choose to face the monster Roshan,
ก็อาจเลือกที่จะเผชิญหน้ากับ อสูรกาย Roshan
who guards the Aegis of the Immortal.
ผู้ปกป้อง Aegis of the Immortal
A unique item which allows a slain hero
ไอเท็มพิเศษซึ่งช่วยให้ฮีโร่ที่ถูกสังหาร
to immediately return to life.
ฟื้นคืนชีพขึ้นมาทันที
After the towers are eliminated,
หลังจากที่ทำลายป้อมได้แล้ว
players may begin assaulting the opposing team's base.
ผู้เล่นอาจเริ่มจู่โจมฐานของฝ่ายตรงข้ามได้
Within each base are several sets of barracks,
ในฐานแต่ละแห่งมีบาร์แร็กจำนวนหนึ่ง
which if destroyed, will strengthen
ซึ่งหากทำลายลงได้ จะช่วยเสริมความแข็งแกร่ง
the forces of the attacking team.
ให้กับกองกำลังของทีมที่โจมตี
Beyond the barracks lies the Ancient itself,
พ้นจากบาร์แร็กไปคือ ที่ตั้งของ Ancient เอง
protected by a final group of defensive towers.
ซึ่งมีป้อมคุ้มกันกลุ่มสุดท้ายคอยปกป้องอยู่
The match ends if either teams' Ancient is destroyed.
แมตช์จะสิ้นสุดเมื่อ Ancient ของทีมใดทีมหนึ่งถูกทำลาย
This is Dota.
นี่คือ Dota